# Joaquín Mesa

Buenos Aires, Argentina  $\cdot$  joacomesa@gmail.com  $\cdot$  Linkedin: Joaquín Mesa  $\cdot$  Portfolio: joacomesa.com.ar

## FRONT-END DEVELOPER & DESIGNER

Front-end developer with a focus on UX and advanced Digital Communication student. My skills as a developer are complemented by my knowledge in design and user experience. Also, artificial intelligence has become a fundamental tool in my professional life. I am a consistent, resourceful, and self-taught person who enjoys teamwork and am always open to learn new skills and technologies.

#### **SKILLS**

**Technologies**: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Sass, Astro, Next JS, SQL, PHP

**Tools**: GitHub, Git, Firebase, Figma, Photoshop, Wordpress **Others**: UX / UI Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, SEO

Languages: Spanish, English (C1 IELTS)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Freelance Web Developer & Designer

January 2023 - Present

- Web interface wireframing, designing and prototyping in Figma
- Development and maintenance of accesible, scalable and responsive websites
- Communication with clients

#### Project Management Internship - Delateral

December 2023 - August 2024

Trainee role

- Worked in branding, communication and digital marketing projects.
- Websites and web platforms management using Wordpress, HTML, CSS and JS.
- Weekly meetings with the team and clients.
- Refactoring of the company website.

## Assistant Professor - University of Palermo

August 2023 - July 2024

#### In two courses:

Digital Production III (Web Development | HTML - CSS - JS - PHP - SQL) - Prof. Mariano Ingerto Interactive Communication III (UX / UI Design) - Prof. Álvaro Ghisolfo

- Lessons planning
- Student support in coding and design projects
- Helped students to code dynamic websites with HTML, CSS, JS, PHP and SQL
- Helped students to design, prototype and test user-friendly applications in Figma

## Data Entry - Fundación Kaleidos

December 2021 - January 2022

- Data entry in Wordpress
- Microsoft Excel
- Multimedia searching, selecting and editing

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's Degree in Digital Communication**

University of Palermo 2021 - Present

### **COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION**



Front-end React Development Coderhouse



**UX / UI Specialization**California Institute of Arts - Coursera